In this class, we will learn about the basic manufacturing process of clothing through the production of a dress.
First, open the picture library.
In Connect, select Cloth Training.
Search for core tools.
Open the core tools basic process to make a dress.
Open Cloth picture library.
Select virtual model .
Insert the model face.
Close the picture library.
You can see that the current version is only one side.
So we need to match the version.
First, we need to open the front.
Before operation, we first understand three ways to open.
You can see this picture.
Here includes the symmetry open editor and sewing line.
Open.
Close the cover.
They can all be based on the selected line.
Open as a symmetrical panel.
Symmetry open editor and sewing line panel.
The left and right sides can link the editor panel and sewing line.
Open is to open the panel symmetrically.
But it is not linked.
Just turn on the panel game.
We only go to match the panel porque it only opens the panel in theanter.
It does not include the inside and the basis space and the left and right are not linked.
Now we will slave the editing panel.
Lecturerppers the two consumed on their to- dáfid front and middle line.
Press Shift platform to …
реб позвол k Wikileaks
On the yellow bar, click the functional erschütter.
Select to open the edit sewing line.
Next, let's fill in the remaining sheets.
Select the adjustment sheet tool.
Click on the sleeve on the right.
You can copy and paste the sheets, and paste the mirror.
If you need to copy the sheets to be able to link the editor, you need to use the Cron link sheet tool.
There are three ways to copy and paste.
Before operation, let's go through this picture to understand the difference between them.
The Cron sheet is divided into symmetrical sheet, sheet and sewing line, and symmetrical sheet, and link sheet.
Symmetrical sheet, sheet and sewing line are the sheets that copy and paste a symmetrical sheet, and the sheet and sewing line can link the editor.
Symmetrical sheet refers to the sheet that is linked to the editor.
The Cron sheet is symmetrical and linked, but the sewing line is not linked.
Link sheet is a sheet with the same shape as the Cron sheet, and it can link the editor, but the sewing line is not linked.
And we can see symmetrical sheet, sheet and sewing line, and symmetrical sheet and link sheet.
The color of their external frame line is different.
Next, in the 2D window.
Select the remaining sheet.
Click the right button.
Select the Cron link sheet.
Symmetrical sheet, sheet and sewing line, Cron out the other half of the sheet.
And you can sort them out.
Here, we suggest that the front is placed near the model's shadow.
The sleeve is placed on both sides of the front.
The sleeve is placed near the model's shadow.
We should pay attention to the front sleeve, which should be near the front piece.
The position of the back piece is on the other side of the sleeve.
The purpose of arranging it this way is to clearly understand the structure of the sheet,
in order to improve the speed and accuracy of the subsequent sewing.
After 2D arrangement,
You can arrange the board on the model in the 3D window.
Open the arrangement on the model.
You can see that the current board
blocked some of the arrangements on the model.
We can press Ctrl and A to select all the boards,
then use the green axis on the positioning ball
to move the board up.
So the arrangement on the model will not be blocked.
Then select the board.
Arrange the board on the model through the arrangement point.
You can also use the positioning ball
to move the board a little bit.
You can switch the view.
Arrange the board of the sleeve.
Press the eight cuts on the keyboard to switch to the back view.
Arrange the board on the back.
Press the eight cuts on the keyboard to switch to the front view.
You can press Shift to select two more boards.
Use the green axis on the positioning ball to move it down.
And use the blue axis to move it a little bit to the front of the screen.
So we have arranged all the boards.
The gold board here
will be arranged later when sewing.
Press Shift plus F.
Here you can see that the board on the model is now ready to be sewn.
Then we can use the two or three D windows to choose the sewing tool and add the sewing line.
Now we start sewing.
Sew according to a certain order to avoid missing.
For example, we are currently sewing from the top to the bottom.
Here,
we can press the Shift to sew one pair more.
and complete the sewing line of the back piece.
Add the sewing line from top to bottom.
Now the front and back pieces are sewn.
Then sew all parts together.
Here you need to pay attention.
The panel piece needs to be sewn according to the corresponding cutout position.
Here we need to switch to the free sewing tool.
The position of the front and back pieces of clothing.
Because it is a pair of more sewing,
so we need to press Shift to do a pair of more sewing.
Next, you can sew the sewing line in the switching position tool.
Make up the sewing line.
Finally, sew the sleeve to tighten the panel piece.
The current sleeve panel piece is a blue-purple basic line.
Mainly used to mark.
Sewing line tools and switching to the border tool.
There is no way to select this line.
We need to convert it to the internal line.
Do the editing and sewing.
In the 2D tool bar, find the loop outline tool.
Select this basic line.
Press the return key on the keyboard to complete the loop.
Use the editing panel tool to click on the 2D window background.
You can see that the current loop outline tool is selected.
You can see that the current loop outline has become a red-brown internal line.
And now you can select it.
Switch to the sewing line tool.
Add the sewing line to the panel piece of the sleeve.
Here you need to pay attention.
The part of the overlapping sewing line needs to be selected.
Then select the panel piece in the 3D window.
Click the right button.
Select to add to the inside.
So the loose panel piece is based on the sewing line.
It was added to the inside of the sleeve panel piece.
Now we have completed all the sewing.
Press the control button on the keyboard to start the simulation.
You can see that the clothing is in the use of the sewing line and gravity.
It's ready to wear.
Use your hand to adjust the clothing wear effect.
Then press the control button on the keyboard to close the simulation.
Because the front is a double-layer structure.
Use the adjustment panel tool.
Select the panel piece.
Click the right button on the front.
The panel piece is divided into the outer and the inner.
At this time, we select the outer of the panel piece.
Then click the left button on the blank on the top of the front.
Complete the outer panel piece.
Switch to the editing sewing line tool.
You can check the panel piece and the round panel piece.
The sewing line between them is automatically generated.
And the panel piece outer line is also automatically selected.
At the same time, the original form is attached to the 3D clothing.
A new layer of panel piece is added.
Then we can simulate.
You can see that it is actually a double-layer panel piece.
Then change the model's posture to a vertical posture.
Press the Y on the keyboard to open the drawing.
Select the close drawing.
Model female model posture.
Select the vertical posture.
Drag it to the 3D window.
Open the posture.
The model's default posture is a double-layer posture.
Convenient to arrange and simulate clothing.
After doing the clothing,
Change to a vertical posture.
Convenient to check the wear and tear effect of clothing.
Press the Y on the keyboard to close the drawing.
After changing the posture,
You can see that at the 3D window,
There are blue lines on the clothing.
And there are red lines at the sleeve.
This is the basic line on the panel piece.
You can see that there are blue lines on the clothing.
And there are red lines on the sleeve.
This is the basic line and the inner line on the panel piece.
In order to show the clothing better,
You can find the clothing information display on the 3D window vertical menu bar.
Click to cancel the display of the inner line and the basic line.
Then apply the fabric.
Press the Y to open the drawing.
Select the fabric in Connect.
Enter lace and click to search.
Then select free here.
Select this lace gauze fabric.
Double-click to increase to the object window.
Click to confirm.
Click to close.
Close the picture library.
Select this fabric.
Then open Color tool.
Enter the color number 114101.
Press the back button to search for the color.
Select the color, and select to add.
Add it to the user's custom color palette.
Click to confirm.
Then select the application and turn it off.
Then use the adjustment panel tool to select the sleeves and the panels on the outside of the front panel.
You can press Shift to select more.
Apply this lace fabric to these panels.
Then press the Y on the keyboard to open the sketchbook.
Select the Cloth sketchbook, select the fabric.
Find the V2, shrink, bulge, two fabrics.
Drag it to the fabric.
Loosen the left mouse button to complete the replacement of the fabric.
Then give this fabric a name.
Select the color you just added.
Select the application and turn it off.
Finally, in the 2D window,
press Shift to select more sleeve elastic band panels.
Use the elastic band fabric in the sketchbook.
Select the elastic band.
Then drag the elastic band fabric on the panel to apply.
Turn off the sketchbook.
Open the simulation.
You can see that the application of different fabrics makes the wear and tear effect and the wrinkle effect different.
Press the control key on the keyboard to close the simulation.
Then use the edit panel tool.
Select the neck line.
You can see that the current length of the 3D line is longer than the length of the 2D line.
This shows that the fabric of the neck is stretched.
To optimize the process, press Shift to select more sleeve panels.
Then, in the right-hand attribute editor, select the elastic.
Below appears the elastic ratio and the strength of the elasticity.
The elastic ratio means that the shrinkage amount simulated in 3D by the ratio control line is determined here.
This is 80%.
This shows that this line will simulate the original length of 80% in the 3D window.
The strength of elasticity means that the length of the 3D window is 80%.
When simulation, this line maintains the strength of the strength of 80% length.
The larger, the less likely to be stretched.
Now need to avoid the neck line is stretched.
Set the elastic ratio to 100%.
Set the elastic ratio to 100%
In the back waist and sleeve.
Is the regular and long edge sewing.
In order to maintain the short edge and not be pulled and deformed,
it can also be set to a 100% flexible ratio.
Press Shift to select more of these lines, and select Flexibility.
Unify the flexible ratio to 100%.
Change the angle, and then open the simulation.
You can see the change in the clothing after applying the 100% flexible ratio.
Close the simulation.
After completing all the steps that need to be simulated, the last step is to improve the quality of the clothing.
Click the button to improve the quality of the clothing in the 3D tool bar.
There are several attribute options here.
First of all, the clothing here has a particle diameter.
The thickness of the plate is conflict.
The virtual model here has a surface diameter and a simulation quality.
Here are a few pictures to understand the meaning of these parameters.
First is the particle diameter.
The particle diameter of the clothing refers to the distance between the two points of the clothing grid.
The smaller the particle diameter, the more grid.
And the shape of the clothing is simulated.
It is also more delicate.
The corresponding simulation speed will also slow down.
Therefore, it is recommended to make larger plates.
Finally, reduce the particle diameter of the clothing.
The thickness of the plate.
Conflict.
It is intended to prevent the surface from protruding during the simulation process.
And the safety distance set on the surface of the plate.
Its default value is 2.5 mm.
After the particle diameter is reduced, it can be reduced to 1.
You can see the effect between the plates when there is a different conflict thickness in the picture.
The surface diameter of the model refers to the layer between the plate and the model.
And the safety distance set on the model surface.
Its default value is 3 mm.
Reducing the surface diameter of the model will also make the clothing closer to the model.
Next is the quality of the simulation.
Here you can choose the normal speed or the test wear speed.
The normal speed of the simulation will be faster.
It is better to balance the simulation speed and accuracy.
The test wear simulation is a more accurate physical characteristic of the simulation fabric.
In order to get a more accurate clothing effect.
The speed will be slower.
Usually when checking the test body, use the simulation mode.
Finally, use the tool to improve the quality of the clothing.
The particle diameter is changed to 5 mm.
The conflict thickness is changed to 1 mm.
The surface diameter of the model is reduced to 0 mm.
The simulation quality can be used with normal speed simulation.
Click OK.
And open the simulation by pressing the control key on the keyboard.
You can see that the clothing simulation is more delicate and realistic.
Close the simulation and go back to the positive second view.
You can save this dress.
Select the file.
Save the project file.
Save this dress.
If you make a mistake, it makes an error.
And the dialog box from the simulation file will be fogged.
To make Airsoft movie here, step back to this screen.
Right click and select the flight surface.
Click OK
This time, the好好 look of the product will disappear.
Click on the anomaly and change it directly.
Change the layer color.
Click OK
The glaze will disappear now.
As previously seen in the video, the 그거 tolerance can be altered to 10 degrees.